Alden Davidson

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software engineering professional with experience developing and designing full-stack applications using modern web technologies. Strong interest in continuous learning and using new tools to improve products and processes. Focused on producing valuable user outcomes through user-centered design.

SKILLS.

Languages & Tools: Azure Kubernetes Services, CSS, Docker, Git, Kotlin, Linux, LATEX, React, React Native, Spring, SQL, TypeScript Practices: Agile Software Development, Continuous Integration, Extreme Programming, Test-Driven Development, User-Centered Design

WORK HISTORY

Feb 2024 – Current

Software Engineer (SkillBridge Intern)

Sagely | Remote

- Built a social learning platform to guide users' personal and professional learning journeys, using TypeScript, React, and TailwindCSS.
- Integrated OpenAI's GPT using LangChain and Jina Reader to organize, curate, and contextualize user content
- Ensured feature parity on both web and mobile applications to create a consistent user experience

Jan 2022 – Feb 2024

Full-Stack Software Engineer

United States Space Force | Los Angeles, CA

- Developed and sustained two full-stack applications, using TypeScript, React, Kotlin, and Spring, to modernize satellite management for 1200+ global users
- Transitioned two applications from Cloud Foundry to Azure Kubernetes Services as tracers for new deployment pipeline and environment
- Led scoping of project to allocate satellite resources from multiple locations, at the request of the USSF Chief of Space Operations

Nov 2019 – Dec 2021

Project Manager

United States Space Force | Los Angeles, CA

- Planned, scheduled, and negotiated \$28M follow-on for \$34M project
- Monitored project performance to identify and implement improvements
- Supervised cross-functional team of 8 to manage project issues and risks
- Presented detailed weekly project status updates to users, executive management, and other stakeholders

EDUCATION_

May 2019

Bachelor of Science: Computer Engineering

Rochester Institute of Technology | Rochester, NY